Guide to the Libby Brown Collection on Dorothy Dean MSS.452
Fales Library and Special Collections
Libby Brown Collection on Dorothy Dean
1980-1987
Fales Library and Special Collections
Brown, Libby
MSS.452
1.25 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 small artifact box
Dorothy Dean (December 22, 1932–February 13, 1987) was a social figure, member of Andy Warhol's Factory, writer and editor in New York in the 1960s and 1970s. This collection consists of materials collected by Libby Brown created by Dorothy Dean that were accumulated during their friendship. Materials include calendars, notebooks, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and a roladex primarily from the period of Dean's life after she left New York in 1980 until her death in 1987.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials collected by Libby Brown that are about or where created by Dorothy Dean that Brown accumulated during their friendship. Materials include calendars, notebooks, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and a roladex primarily from the period of Dean's life after she left New York in 1980 until her death in 1987. The correspondence primarily concerns Dean's professional work outside of New York, as well as her efforts to keep in contact with her social and artistic circle from New York. This collection also includes multiple obituaries on Dean.
Related Materials
Joe Campbell Collection of Dorothy Dean Letters 1964-1987 (MSS 222)
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are organized in the order in which they were received.
Biographical / Historical
Dorothy Dean (December 22, 1932–February 13, 1987) was a social figure, member of Andy Warhol's Factory, writer and editor in New York in the 1960s and 1970s. Born in White Plains, New York, Dean attended Radcliffe College before earning a master's degree in Fine Arts from Harvard College. After moving to New York, Dean established herself as part of Andy Warhol's Factory and appeared in several Factory films, including My Hustler and Afternoon, while also working at famed nightclub and artistic hangout, Max's Kansas City. She also held brief editorial and proofreading positions at several publications including The New Yorker and Vogue. In 1980, Dean moved to Boulder, Colorado where she worked in a bookstore and as an editor and lived until she died of cancer in 1987.
Sources:
Als, Hilton. The Women. New York: Farrar Straus Giroux, 1998. pp. 67-117.
Watson, Steven. Factory Made: Andy Warhol and the Sixties. New York: Pantheon Books, 2003.
Martin, Nicholas. Guide to the Joe Campbell Collection of Dorothy Dean Letters (MSS 222).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Libby Brown, March 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.010.
Correspondence.; African Americans -- Intellectual life; Artists and community -- United States; Dean, Dorothy
- Notebook, circa 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Day Planner, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Notebooks, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Dorothy Dean Obituary, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Truman Capote, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11-18)
- Notebook, circa 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21-26)
- Writings in Cheetah Binder, circa 1980-1987 (Box 1)
- Roladex, circa 1980-1987 (Box 2)